All right, before we go further, I need
to teach you another way of storing
data. What we've done so far is I've
shown you how arrays work. Arrays store
data. You remember I brought in a
multicolored thing that had multiple
boxes. And in each of the boxes, labeled
by number, I could put information.
Well, what I'm about to teach you is
called an object. Objects, instead of
storing information in order, like an
array with 0, one, two, um, objects
store them by name. Um, in fact, objects
are really cool. They're one of my
favorite programming tools. Um, in fact,
my favorite um my favorite way to
program is called object-oriented
programming, but that is a little bit
beyond this course, sadly. So, maybe
another time. Um, but for now, I'm just
going to teach you the basics of
JavaScript objects. So, in order to do
that, I have brought
a dictionary. Um, yes, I did have to go
to the library to get one of these
because I don't own a dictionary. That's
what Google's for. Um, but if I wanted
to find something in a dictionary, then
let's say I wanted to look up um the
definition of defenestration. So, what I
would do is I would open up my
dictionary,
search through until I found the word
I'm looking for. And in this case,
defenistration
is right here. and it says the action of
throwing someone or something out of a
window. So notice how I used the
dictionary. What I did is I looked up by
name something that I wanted. So I
looked up the word defenistration. Next
to defenistration there was information
and that information was the definition
of the word. Um objects work like this
in JavaScript. um they have something
that you look up with and that thing
that you look up um has information
stored there. So just like I could look
up in this book the word defenistration
and it gave me a definition in my
JavaScript object, I could look
something up by name and it'll give me
the value stored. So I'm just going to
look up another definition in here.
Tired. How do they take my picture?